

Matthew Hobbs

E-mail: Matthew.p.hobbs@gmail.com Website: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/matthewphol

Personal Statement

Accomplished, motivated and versatile Solution Architect and Consultant with 12 years of experience in the IT industry ranging from engineer, consultancy and architecting projects. known for a personable approach to clients and co-workers as well as for delivering and implementing advanced hardware solutions to small and medium-size businesses, seeking the next big career challenge and an opportunity to apply my knowledge and expertise on a larger scale. Innovative and driven, consistent overachiever, excellent co-ordinator and organiser, responsible and efficient project manager.

Technical Expertise

Being a generalist I have a lot of skills in many different areas, but my strongest expertise is in the following areas:

- (5.5 years) Microsoft Azure
- (6.5 years) Office 365
- (11 years) Microsoft Windows Server 2003 2016 (AD, DNS, DHCP, RADIUS, ADFS, ADCS, GPO, WSUS etc)
- (7 years) Microsoft Exchange Server 2003 2016
- (1 year) Amazon AWS
- (7 years) Virtualisation (VMware and Hyper-V)
- (7 years) Migration tools such as Migration Wiz, Quest, BinaryTree
- (5 years) Managed Services (GFI, AEM)
- (12 years) Various AV solutions (Trend, ESET, Kaspersky, Symantec, AVG)
- (2 years) Avaya VOIP systems
- (12 years) Backup solutions (Ahsay, Asigra, nScaled, Acronis, Backup Exec)
- (8 years) Firewalls (Fortinet, SonicWall, Draytek, Cisco)
- (5 years) Team leading / Managem ent
- (6 months) Forensic analysis tooling (Relativity, Nuix, SEAL, iPro, Tableau, Intralinks)

A full list can be found on my LinkedIn page: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/matthewphobbs

Work experience

EY Jan 2019 — July 19

Senior Azure Architect / Consultant

- · Working with client business implementing solutions for enterprise clients
- Implement the roadmaps for Cloud Architecture and Services (Azure IaaS & PaaS)
- Conduct proof of concept (POC) and implement the design in Azure PaaS
- Development of automated solutions to monitor and support software development and release processes.
- Experience in Azure PaaS technology like Azure Service Bus, APIM, SQLMI, AzureDevOps, Express Route.
- Integration/development and Implementation with 3rd party services using Azure PaaS components.
- Architecture and Implementation experience in Azure Disaster Recovery.
- Forensic Analysis tools such as Relativity, Nuix, SEAL
- · On Premise to Azure migrations

Insight UK Nov 17 — Dec 18

Consultant & Architect

• Develop strong business relationship with customers to understand requirements, project scope and be able to integrate solutions with existing systems to deliver their solution to their satisfaction

- Develop strong business relationships with vendors so that you have up to date knowledge of developing technology and are able to articulate this to customers
- Responsible for project management of the solution, including development, implementation, configuration, integration, testing and optimisation of bespoke customer solutions
- Responsible for providing pro active technical support to customers and has ownership for resolving technical issues that may arise
- Accountable for development of documentation that is used by internal and external partners to deliver technology solutions to defined standards, to troubleshoot deployments or for onward development
- · A flexible approach to working is required to ensure that projects are completed in scope and on time
- Engage in the pre-sale cycle and will provide Infrastructure consultancy, including audits and assessments to support the sales team in their proposals

Technologies used:

Microsoft Azure / Office 365 / Exchange / VMware / Hyper-V / Networking / Firewall / AV / Backup / Infrastructure

Ensono

Feb 2017 — Nov 2017

Solution Architect

- Client aligned Solution Architect designing detailed and complex solutions on various cloud and hybrid platforms such as AWS, Azure and Service provider cloud for three large/enterprise existing clients. Approximate users per client: 5000
- Client design knowledge management; understanding key indicators, pain points and strategy direction for aligned clients to assist in building the right solutions
- Proactive Capacity and lifecycle management; understanding in great detail Ensono's product portfolio to assist on presales opportunities for aligned clients whilst also taking into considering ROI, OPEX/CAPEX models, depreciation etc
- Continual service improvement and recommendations for clients business units and internal design guides, build guides etc
- · Input into RFIs, ITTs, RFPs, RFQ's as and when required
- Technical pre-sales meetings with board level management as well as lower level management for up and coming solutions and renewals
- Technical sign off for solution design documents within the solution architect team (peer reviewing)
- Creation of client roadmaps and short/medium term strategies so support client growth

Technologies used:

Microsoft Azure / Office 365 / AWS / VMware / Networking / AV / Backup / Infrastructure

LAN2LAN Ltd

December 2013 — Feb 2017

Senior Technical Consultant, Team Business Leader & Solution Architect

- Team business leader for Microsoft and Managed services teams (manage staff, ensure competencies and qualifications are kept up to date, help drive business within both areas).
- Design and strategize solutions for clients on all platforms, internal upgrades, migrations to azure, office 365 etc
- Coordinate information gathering for architecture templates, documentation filing, creation of architecture documentation and diagrams
- Scope, project manage and implement projects for customers for virtualisation (VMware and Hyper-V), hardware upgrades, migrations (exchange 2007/10 > O365, server 2003 > 2012 / Azure etc).
- Act as a Technical Account Manager for large customers creating IT strategies and working with members of the board to help establish short medium and long time goals.
- Design and build new bespoke networks, infrastructures, and systems for new and existing customers.
- PreSales consultancy for large-scale cloud projects including commercials
- · Provide 3rd line support for customers and as an escalation point for internal staff members
- · Mentor junior staff members.
- Continually review system processes and company procedures to ensure the technical team are as efficient as possible.

Migrated circa 60 environments from Domino and Exchange to Office 365. The smaller migrations through Migration Wiz
and the larger ones through Binary Tree. Largest migration size in mailbox numbers circa 10,000 from 3 separate
exchange servers based around the world.

Technologies used:

On-Prem infrastructure / Exchange / Office 365 / Microsoft Azure / AV / networking / VMware / Hyper-V

Evolve Computers

June 2012 — Dec 2013

Senior Server Support Technician

- Provide level 2nd and 3rd line support
- · Ensure support requests are handled within the SLA
- Identify project opportunities
- Oversee and manage customer backup reviews, system documentation etc.
- · Manage Shift and onsite schedule management
- · Oversee morning checks and server patching / reboots
- · Manage the escalations queue
- · Manage both internal and external projects throughout the entire project life cycle

Technologies used:

Office 365 / Exchange / Infrastructure / Backup / Networking

Aplus Learning Innovations

March 2011 — June 2012

IT Network & e-Learning Platforms Manager

- Manage IT team members and increase productivity.
- · Manage department budget.
- Manage the purchasing of all software, hardware and other IT supplies at the regional level.
- Develop Moodle, Mahara and the websites.
- Promote e-learning culture and develop relevant tools and programs.
- To create resources in various formats that meet to requirements for all departments.
- Manage and maintain the network infrastructure for both sites on weekends and evenings if required.

Technologies used:

Infrastructrure / Exchange / AV / Backup / Networking / LAMP

Academy of Training

October 2009 — March 2011

IT Team Leader, e-Developer, Technician and Trainer

I managed a small and highly skilled team of technicians on their day to day activities whilst I developed resources for our VLE, maintained the companies network for both sites and trained staff in any areas of IT when required.

Older positions available upon request.

Recent Projects

Five most recent projects:

- <u>Large Azure Transformation</u>: End to end migration of 744 on premise VMware servers to Azure. Principal migration engineer role creating migration path process and migrating actual servers using ASR.
- Office 365 Migration: Work along the client's existing IT infrastructure to audit and migrate 4000 mailboxes from Exchange 2010 to Office 365.
- Azure & Office 365 Migration: Design Citrix to Azure migration to move existing 26 Xenapp farm servers to Azure to benefit from auto scaling functionality (scale based on pre-set metrics). This involved auditing the clients existing Citrix farm, designing the new solution, running work shops, POC then implementation of the design. Migration from Exchange 2007 for 300 mailboxes to Office 365 with single sign-on with AAD.
- Office 365 Migration: Lead architect designing the high level strategy for migrating 2000 mailboxes to Ofice 365 and implementing Sharepoint as a file repository.
- Azure CICD PAAS platform migration: Migrating existing VMware infrastructure to Azure's PAAS offerings using Agile methodology. TFS for the pipeline.
- Office 365 Migration: Original consultancy role to audit existing infrastructure for the client which lead onto the architecting and implementation of Hybrid Office 365.

Qualifications

- Microsoft Architecting Microsoft Azure Solutions 70-534 (In progress)
- Microsoft MCSA Office 365
- Microsoft MCSA Server 2012
- Ruckus Certified Network Administrator
- Customer Service Level 3 and 4

Older expired qualifications:

- eCPD Professional Development Adviser
- PAT qualified, various IT technology forums and events, CLAiT Plus, ITQ Lv3, Subject Learning Coach, A1 Assessors Award, Dell Certified Diagnostic Engineer (Pass – 100/100), Novel Netware 6.5 course